CRAIG T. CHOSNEY

Portfolio: ctchosney.github.io
ctchosney@gmail.com

Phone: 740-973-4331

Area: Las Vegas, NV 89135

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated and detail-oriented analyst with a passion for using data to improve business performance and constituent experience. Graduate work focus on quantifying the efficacy of DEI initiatives in the HR and employment sector. Expert team leadership, planning, and organizational skills developed during successful hospitality career.

WORK HISTORY

Freelance - Data Analytics Consultant

United States • 09/2022 - Current

- Partnered with non-profit HR clients to assist in EEO reporting, HRIS analytics, and leveraging ADP Workforce Now for efficient data management and compliance.
- Conducted comprehensive data analysis to identify trends and insights, developed customized dashboards and reports, contributing to strategic decision-making and improved operations.

Freemans Restaurant - Manager and Captain

New York, NY • 08/2012 - 12/2024

- Handled customer complaints professionally, resolving issues through diplomatic acknowledgment and commitment to service, resulting in a 20% positive increase in Resy analytics customer ratings.
- Delivered in-depth training to workers in customer-facing roles to promote strong team performance.

| PROJECTS

"Driving Towards Wage Equity With Machine Learning: Predicting Annual Wages by Job Title" • 2024

- Utilized RStudio and Python to construct a machine learning model that predicts future compensation per job title.
- Created a deliverable for potential use by an organization to promote a more equitable wage dispersion.

"Minority Representation in Museum Sector Employment, 2014-2020" and "Measuring Factors for Museum Sector Income Inequality, 2016-2021" • 2022-2023

- Compiled, cleaned, and manipulated EEO-1 and IPUMS USA ACS data in R and STATA for proper handling and statistical analysis.
- Developed polished visualizations to share results.

EDUCATION

CUNY Graduate Center. New York, NY

• 12/2024, Summa cum laude

Master of Science: Quantitative Methods and Data Analytics

Advanced Certificate: Data Science

Coursera. Online • 08/2023

Certificate: Google Data Analytics

New York University. New York, NY • 05/2022

Certificate: Computer Science, Tandon School of Engineering Preparatory Course

Parsons School of Design. New York, NY

• 12/2007

Associate of Applied Science: Marketing And Communication

Denison University. Granville, OH

• 05/2005, Magna cum laude

Bachelor of Arts: Sociology/ Anthropology/Geology

SKILLS

- Data Visualization: Flourish, R Studio/ ggplot2, Matplotlib, Tableau
- Modeling: linear regression, logistic regression
- Programming: C++, Python, R, STATA
- Statistical analysis

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Big Data Analytics
- Data Mining
- Data Visualization
- Machine Learning
- Quantitative Research Methods
- Sociological Statistics
- Simulation and Modeling Techniques